<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>interacting with modules on darktable user manual</title>
    <link>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/</link>
    <description>Recent content in interacting with modules on darktable user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>module header</title>
      <link>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/module-header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/module-header/</guid>
      <description>At the top of each image operation module is the module header.
IMAGE HERE
Click on the module header to expand the module and display the parameters that control its operation.
By default darktable will only allow one processing module to be expanded at a time. If you click the header of another module, the previous module controls are collapsed. If you want to see more than one module expanded, you may expand further modules with Shift+click: all previously expanded modules will remain open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>multiple instances</title>
      <link>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/multiple-instances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/multiple-instances/</guid>
      <description>Many of darktable&amp;rsquo;s modules can be applied more than once in the pixelpipe. Each instance of a module behaves like any other module, taking its input from the module below in the pixelpipe delivering its output to the module above.
As with the base instance of a module, all instances can be moved independently within the pixelpipe either by holding Ctrl+Shift while dragging &amp;amp; dropping or by choosing &amp;ldquo;move up&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;move down&amp;rdquo; in the multiple instances drop-down menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>presets</title>
      <link>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/presets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/presets/</guid>
      <description>Presets allow you to store commonly used module settings for future use. Some modules already come with pre-defined presets but you can also define your own. Both internal and user-defined presets can be shown by clicking the presets menu in the module header.
the presets menu The presets menu will contain one or more of the following entries depending on the presets that are defined or selected for the module:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>module controls</title>
      <link>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/module-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/module-controls/</guid>
      <description>sliders Sliders offer five different ways of interaction, depending on the level of control you require.
 left-click Click anywhere in the slider area to set the value. You can also click and drag to change it. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to aim for the triangle or even the line - you may click anywhere in the entire height of the slider including the label. mouse wheel Hover over the slider with your mouse, then use your mouse wheel to adjust the value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>curves</title>
      <link>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/curves/</guid>
      <description>Three image processing modules (base curve, tone curve and rgb curve) use curves to control the tones in the image. These modules have some common features that deserve separate discussion.
nodes In their default state, curves are straight lines, defined by two anchor nodes. You can move the nodes to modify the curve or generate new nodes by clicking on the curve. With Ctrl+click you can generate a new node at the x-location of the mouse pointer and the corresponding y-location of the current curve &amp;ndash; this adds a node without the risk of accidentally modifying the curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wavelets</title>
      <link>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/wavelets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/wavelets/</guid>
      <description>Wavelets are a technique used in image processing to separate an image into a number of layers, each containing a different level of detail. After decomposing an image in this way, a processing module can limit its processing to one or more of those layers, and then piece the image back together again at the end. This allows us to be surgical about which features in the image we wish to impact when working with a module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>searching for and grouping modules (ToDo)</title>
      <link>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/search-and-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elstoc.github.io/dtdocs/darkroom/interacting-with-modules/search-and-group/</guid>
      <description>Summarise the ways in which modules can be grouped (module groups) and searched.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
